Jiasheng Gu

Homepage GitHub LinkedIn Email: jiashengguwen@gmail.com Phone: +86 17701621592

Research Interests

My research interest lies in the fields of natural language processing and generation, along with reliable and efficient methods for interconverting between natural language and different forms of data.

Long-term research goal: Use artificial intelligence to turn natural language into a bridge to various tasks.

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

Honor M.S. in Machine Learning and Data Science Aug. 2021 - May. 2023 Relevant Courses: Deep Learning, Probability, Linear Algebra, Parallel Computing *GPA: 4.0/4.0 (100%)*

Xidian University

Xian, Shaanxi

B.E. in Telecommunications Engineering Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

Relevant Courses: Data Structure, Calculus, Discrete Mathematics

GPA: 3.6/4.0 (90%, Top 10%)

Publications

Robustness of learning from task instructions

Jiasheng Gu, Hongyu Zhao, Hanzi Xu, Liangyu Nie, Hongyuan Mei, Wenpeng Yin ACL 2023 findings, *Arxiv*

Co-evolving Data-driven and NLU-driven Synthesizers for Generating Code in Domain Growth and Data Scarcity

Jiasheng Gu, Zifan Nan, Zhiyuan Peng, Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng Shen *EMNLP workshop 2023*

Research Experience

Pennsylvania State University

• Mentor: Wenpeng Yin

June. 2022 - Oct. 2022

- Project: Robustness of learning from task instructions
- Contribution: Experimented and analyzed the robustness of the instruction-tuned model on perturbed instructions.
- Publication: Arxiv

North Carolina State University

• Mentors: Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng Shen

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Project: Zero-shot Code Generation via Rule-AI Co-learning from Document
- Contribution: Proposed a zero-shot code generation framework combining rule-based and AI-based methods to generate DSL code.
- Publication: EMNLP workshop submission

Shanghai Jiaotong University

• Mentors: Pengfei Liu

April 2023 - June 2023

- Project: Training Large Language Model on Math Tasks repo
- Contribution: Trained(continue pretraining and finetune) LLaMA-13B on well-designed math datasets to improve the performance of math tasks.

University of Southern California

• Mentors: Peter A. Beerel

Aug. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Project: Designing visual networks with very low FLOPs
- Contribution: Proposed a dilated depthwise convolution that captures global information and extensive experiments are done on it.

Dartmouth College

• Mentor: Soroush Vosoughi

May. 2022 - Sep. 2022

- Project: The Evolution of Artificial Intelligence in Bio-Medicine
- Contribution: Proposed a method to analyze artificial intelligence techniques used in biomedical publications.
- Publication: Under review, Journal of Medical Internet Research (JMIR)

ETH Zürich

• Mentor: Yuyi Wang

June. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Project: Designing pre-training tasks for text summarization
- Contribution: Using trained metrics to find the highest-importance sentences as summaries makes the pre-training task more effective.

Industry Experience

Lime

• SDE internship

May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

• Enhanced system scalability by refactoring the timed feature extraction and computation process. Achieved significant improvements in overall system efficiency through optimization of timed computations.

Transwarp

· NLP internship

Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

 Designed and implemented a hybrid long-text summarization system combining extractive and abstractive methods; utilized DGCNN for extractive summarization and leveraged BART for abstractive refinement.

Professional service

Program Committee

• The European Chapter of the ACL (EACL)

2023

ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining(WSDM)

2023 2023

Association for Computational Linguistics(ACL)

2023

Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing(EMNLP)

The Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence(AAAI)

2023

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant, University of Southern California

• EE 503: Probability for Electrical and Computer Engineers

Fall 2022

Awards

USC Ming Hsieh Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Masters Students Honors Program

2021

Skills

Programming

Python, C++, C, R, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, MATLAB

Framework

PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, SciPy

Professional Softwares

Git, LaTeX, SPSS, Mathematica, AWS, GCP, Docker, MongoDB

References

Wenpeng Yin, Assistant Professor

Computer Science and Engineering Department Pennsylvania State University wenpeng@psu.edu

Dongkuan Xu, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University dxu27@ncsu.edu

Xipeng Shen, Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University xshen5@ncsu.edu

Peter A. Beerel, Professor

Ming Hsieh Electrical and Computer Engineering Department University of Southern California pabeerel@usc.edu

Soroush Vosoughi, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College soroush.vosoughi@dartmouth.edu